俺は 運命って言葉が嫌いだ
I hate the word "fate."
生まれ　出会い　別れ
Birth, encounters, partings,
success and failure,
成功と失敗
fortune and misfortune in life.
人生の幸　不幸
If everything is already set in stone by fate,
それらが予め　運命によって決められているのなら
then why are we even born?
俺達は何のために生まれてくるのだろう
裕福な家庭に生まれる人
There are those born wealthy,
美しい母親から生まれる人
those born of beautiful mothers,
and those born into war or poverty.
飢餓や戦争の真っ只中に生まれる人
If that's all caused by fate, then God must be incredibly unfair and cruel.
それらが全て　運命だとすれば
The 36th Antarctic
Environmental Defense Team
神様って奴はとんでもなく理不尽で残酷だ
Because, ever since that day, none of us had a future.
あの時から俺達には　未来なんてなく
ただ決して　何者にも成れないって事だけが　はっきりしていたんだから
The only thing we knew... was that we would never amount to anything.
くるくる回る
<< kurukuru mawaru kimi no hitomi >>
<< Round and round, your eyes wander around >>
君の瞳探して回る
<< sagashite mawaru eki no home >>
<< Searching around the station's platforms >>
駅のホーム
響くファンファーレ
<< hibiku fanfare >>
<< The sound of fanfare from afar >>
ガラガラ音を立てる街
<< garagara oto wo tateru machi >>
<< The clamorous city making noise >>
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
<< toriaezu mimi wo kashite ita no >>
<< I tried to keep an ear out for all this >>
もうすぐ消えるはずの世界に
<< mousugu kieru hazu no sekai ni >>
<< In a world that's about to end >>
ごめんね
<< gomen ne >>
<< I'm sorry >>
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
<< mou nido to aenai youna sonna ki ga shite >>
<< I just had a feeling I would never see you again >>
運命が笑う
<< unmei ga warau >>
<< Fate is laughing at us >>
臨界点突破してんだ
<< rinkaiten toppa shiten da >>
<< I'm already past the point of no return >>
限界なら既に去って
<< genkai nara sude ni satte >>
<< Far over my limit >>
絶対的支配だって
<< zettaiteki shihai datte >>
<< Even your absolute control has >>
崩壊
<< houkai >>
<< Crumbled >>
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
<< shuumatsu riron wa kijou no kuuron shika naitte >>
<< "The end of the world is nothing but a hypothesis" >>
ゼロとイチの世界線の果てから
<< 0 to 1 no sekaisen no hate kara sakebu yo >>
<< Is what I'm crying out from other side of the binary world line >>
叫ぶよ
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
<< mou sugu kimi ga ai ni kuru you na ki ga shite >>
<< I have a feeling you'll come see me soon >>
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作,仅供学习交流之用
若您喜欢本作品,请支持正版影像制品
---诸神字幕组---
日听 xHunter
翻译：英英 校对：凌可乐
时间轴：绯桜闲   压制：笑眯咪
僕は目を閉じるよ
<< boku wa me wo tojiru yo >>
<< So I will be waiting with my eyes closed >>
ただいま
I'm home.
I guess they went out.
何だ　出かけてるのか
We made your favorite, stuffed cabbage, for dinner today.
今日は冠ちゃんの大好きなロール キャベツです
I went with Sho to share some with Ringo,
晶ちゃんと　リンゴちゃんちへお裾分けに行ってくるので
so please reheat it and eat without us.
先にチンして食べてね
From Himari.
ひまり
Maharaja
Sexy Spicy
Girl
It's curry flavor today.
今日はカレー味か
はい　高倉です
Takakura residence.
Hello?
もしもし　どうちら様
Who's this?
Hey! I'm gonna hang up if this is a prank call!
おいー　悪戯なら　切るぞ
Isn't it stimulating?
痺れるだろう
Huh? What?
あー　何
Your sister,
君の妹　高倉ひまりは　今夜また死ぬよ
Takakura Himari,
will die again tonight.
Who the hell are you?
誰だお前
Someone from the Destination of Fate.
運命の至る場所から来た者
What I'm trying to say is, it's our fault your sister died.
だから　君の姉さんが死んだのは僕達のせいなんだ
W-Wait!
ちょ　ちょっと待て
How is Momoka's death your fault?
どうして桃果の亡くなったのが　貴方達のせいなの
16 years ago, many people died.
十六年前　大勢の人が死んだ
And the perpetrators of that incident were my parents!
あの事件起こしたのは　僕達の父さんと母さんなんだ
That Day - The room where it all started - Incident and its turbulence - A boy was born in Takakura family. And he commenced the operation. It was their Survival S...
I see, she had the baby.
ええ　そうですか
生まれましたか
A boy?
男の子か
What about my wife?
それで　妻の方は
Both mother and child are healthy?
母子ともに健康
I'm so glad!
良かった
Yes.
ええ　お世話になりました
Thank you very much.
I'll head over to the hospital as soon as I'm done with work.
私も仕事が片付いたら　すぐそちらの病院へ駆け付けます
Good bye.
では
So...
そうか　男の子か
It's a boy.
LETS INITIATE
THE SURVIVAL STRATEGY
Now, the world will be put at peace.
これで世界は　ピースされる
Tabuki - 16 years ago - Morning of the incident - Tabuki was supposed to take the same train as Momoka. But the alarm never went off. Momoka has...
Sheesh, why didn't my alarm go off today of all days?
もうー　何で今日に限って目覚まし時計鳴らないかな
Kagaya Elementary
Tabuki Keiju
I wonder if Momoka is on the subway already?
桃果ちゃん　もう地下鉄乗っちゃったかな
It's my turn to take care of the animals today...
今日は飼育当番だし
I'll be sentenced to tickling hell again if I'm late!
遅れたら　また擽り地獄の刑だよ
We apologize for the inconvenience.
...at this moment...
We sincerely apologize for the inconvenience...
An accident? In the subway?
事故　地下鉄で
I hear it happened in Kasumigaseki Station.
I heard it was  Kokkai-gijido-mae Station.
It happened in multiple locations, not just on this subway line.
An explosion? How?
The subway… Momoka?!
地下鉄　桃果ちゃん
Excuse me, let me through!
すみません　退いてください
My friend... My friend is in there!
友達が　僕の友達が中に
おい　見ろうよ　あれ
Hey, look over there!
Smoke... Fire?
煙　火事か
Tabuki - Funeral Home - Momoka's funeral - Impossible. I refuse to believe Momoka is dead. Because she...
ホントひどい事件だったわね
What a terrible tragedy.
So many innocent victims!
あんなに沢山人が犠牲になるなんて
Wasn't Momoka still in elementary school?
桃果ちゃん また小学生だったんでしょう
Poor thing.
可哀相に
She happened to get on the train later than usual that day.
あの日に限っていつもの一本遅い電車に乗るなんて
Luck wasn't with her.
運が悪かったわね
There wasn't a trace of her left. They only found her diary.
見つからないそうよ　返ってきた物に日記帳だけだ
Who would've thought her sister would be born on the same day Momoka's died.
それにしても　桃果ちゃんが亡くなったのと同じ日に　荻野目さんが生まれるなんて
What a twist of fate.
何の因果かしらね
I won't believe...
僕は信じんないよ
that you're gone… Momoka.
桃果ちゃん　君がもうこの世にいないなんて
How can I believe it?
だって　そうだろう
You were so excited that you were going to have a little sister!
もうすぐ妹が生まれるんだって　あんなに楽しみにしてたじゃないか
Yes. I refuse to believe that you died in such an accident.
そうさ　僕は信じない
君があんな事故で死ぬなんて
That you would vanish from this world!
この世界から消えてしまうなんて
It's not possible!
そんな事あるわけない
It can't happen!
あって言い訳ないんだ
僕達の両親　高倉剣山と千江美は
16 years ago, my parents, Kenzan and Chiemi Takakura,
were senior members of the organization that caused the pain and suffering of countless innocent people.
十六年前　沢山の人達を傷つけ殺した犯罪組織の 指導的幹部だったんだ
So, my family killed your sister.
だから　君のお姉さんを殺したのは　僕達の家族
あー　あー　長い　長い
Such a long story!
I fell asleep from boredom!
退屈過ぎて　寝ちゃったぞ
Have you accepted the fact that the wheel of fate binds you?
で　お前達
己らを繋ぐ運命の輪に　得心はいたか
Sheesh. Human beings sure are dense creatures.
やれやれ　人と言うのは程々学習能力に乏しい生き物だな
You leave me no choice.
やむを得まい
I'll tell you one last thing.
では　最後に一つだけよい事を教えてやろう
Heave-ho.
ヨッゴ　イショット
聞け　呪われた運命の子らよ
Listen, cursed children of fate!
You have lost the Penguin Drum!
お前達はピングドラムを失った
The world has called forth Dark Bunnies once again!
世界は再び闇兎を呼び込んだ
That's right. The fated day is approaching!
そう　運命の日はすぐそこまで近づいている
What's the matter?
どうしたんだよ
Obtain the Penguin Drum.
ピングドラムを手に入れろ
If you wish to save your sister's life.
妹の命を救いたければ
己を縛る運命から逃れたければ
If you wish to escape the fate that binds you.
If you wish to derail it from its path.
そのレールを切り替えたければ
Find the Penguin Drum and...
ピングドラムを見つけて
Isn't diary the Penguin Drum?
ピングドラムって　日記の事だろう
What can we  do now?
今更どうしろって
Stop... them...
奴を　止めろ
えー
ひまり　ひまり
Himari... Himari!
Himari!
ひまりちゃん
Call an ambulance!
救急車を
The Destination of Fate
That
happened before
I was born.
Bro! Himari collapsed again!
兄貴　ひまりがまた倒れたんだ
The hat's not working... it's different from before.
帽子も効かない
いつもと違う感じで
What should I do? Get your ass over here now!
どうしよう　早く来て
Kanba - Kanba Home -- Kitchen - A certain day I spent with Himari. - Himari always cared for us. I can't lose her. She's the world to me.
My, what a stubborn lass you are.
ふーふー　そなたも強情な女ごよの
Don't play coy! Strip!
これ　大人しく脱がぬか
Oh, no!
あれー　お殿様　お戯れよ
Please stop, Milord!
One layer. Two.
一枚　二枚
I'll strip you bare for my side dish!
全部引ん剝いて　オカズにしてくれるわ
Heehee, I can see your privates!
ほれほれ　大事な所が見えてしまうぞ
Rip!
みりみり
Stuffed cabbage tonight?
今夜はロールキャベツか
Indeed. It is your favorite.
そうじゃ　そなたの大好物じゃぞ
Oh?
うんー
You're making so many!
やけに沢山作るんだな
Does it not take this many to lighten up your mood?
そちの機嫌を取るためには　これぐらい当然じゃ
I can't eat that much.
俺はそんなに食えないぞ
Actually, I'm not in a bad mood to begin with.
っていうか　別に機嫌悪くねぇし
Really?
ホント　じゃ　私のお願い聞いてくれる
Can you do me a favor, then?
Hmm?
Make up with Sho before dinner.
晩御飯までに　晶ちゃんと仲直りする事
もうー　二人ども子供なんだから
You two are so childish.
The great Himari can see right through you!
隠したって　このひまりさんにお見通しなんだからね
Come on, wrap it up.
ほら　これ包んで
おい
You have to make it yourself sometimes.
偶には冠ちゃんが作ってあげなきゃ
Stuffed cabbage is our symbol of reconciliation.
家のロールキャベツは　仲直りの印　でしょう
Right?
I guess so.
そうだったっけな
I'll play the lord and you play the female servant.
じゃ　私がお殿様やるから　腰元は冠ちゃんね
What?
えー　またやるの
You're going to continue?
Of course!
当たり前じゃ
I shall roll you right up, then boil you down!
これからその方　茹でて ぐるぐる巻きにしてやるゆえ
Say your prayers!
覚悟いたせ
Himari...
ひまり　沢山作ってんのはそれがやりたいからだろう
You're making lots just so you can say that, aren't you?
Mary...
メリーさん
Mary Had a Little Lamb.
メリーさんの羊
Mary had three adorable little lambs.
メリーさんは　美しい三匹の小羊を飼っていました
The sight of them walking in the pasture turned everyone's heads.
牧場を連れて歩けば　誰もが振り返ります
The little lambs' wool shone like angels' wings.
小羊達の毛はまるで天使の羽根のよう
Mary couldn't wait to spin their wool into thread.
メリーさんはそれを紡いで糸にする日は待ちきれません
To'oh General Hospital
But one day,
ところが　ある朝　メリーさんは目覚めてびっくり
To'oh General Hospital
Mary awoke to a surprise.
The apple tree in the garden had withered.
庭のリンゴの木が枯れています
It was the first tree in the world.
それは世界で最初の木
The tree that bore golden fruit each year,
毎年　見事な黄金色の実を山のように実らせる
It was Mary's other dear, dear treasure.
メリーさんの大事な大事な　もう一つの御自慢だったのです
Mary ran to the apple tree and broke into tears.
リンゴの木に駆け寄ると　メリーさんは泣き出しました
The apple tree's light had once been the source of world's love, future and dreams.
かつてリンゴの木は　その輝きで世界の未来　夢　愛を照らしていたのです
Now, the world is shrouded in darkness.
世界は闇に包まれてしまいました
Mary cried on and on and the lambs' consolation fell on deaf ears.
メリーさんは泣いて泣いて　小羊達の慰めも耳に届きません
That's when...
そんな時
Shoma!
晶馬
何があった
What happened?
Suddenly, a voice rained down from the sky.
不意に空から声が降って来ました
Don't give up.
諦めないで
The world has
まだ世界は　終わったわけじゃないから
not ended yet.
When Mary looked up, there were two unsual, huge, black bunnies sitting on a rock.
メリーさんは顔をあげると
見たこともない大きな黒い兎が　庭の上に座っていました
Hey! Get yourself together, Shoma!
おい　しっかりしてろ　晶馬
Stop messing around!
ふざけんな
The black bunnies said,
黒い兎は言いました
You know the Shrine of the Goddess deep in the forest?
森の奥に　女神の神殿があるだろう
Go and collect ashes from the flaming torch inside.
そこで燃える松明の灰を取っておいで
This tree will recover the instant you sprinkle the ashes over it!
その灰を撒けば　たちまちこの木は元気になるよ
Mary declined.
メリーさんは首を振りました
女神の火には人が触れてはならないと　掟で決まっていたのです
Their taboo forbade human contact with the torch of the Goddess.
You're just going to borrow some ashes!
灰をちょっと拝借するだけさ
The world will be filled with light once again!
それで世界は　再び光に照らされるんだ
The Goddess will be pleased, too!
女神様だって　お喜びになるさ
That night, Mary stole the ashes from the shrine and sprinkled them over the apple tree.
その夜　メリーさんは神殿の灰を盗んで　リンゴの木に撒きました
ほら　帽子だ
Look, the hat's right here.
You're better now, right?
これで大丈夫だろう　起きろうよ
Wake up!
Come on, I transferred part of my life to you!
なー　俺の命を分け与えたじゃないか
Don't tell me you forgot our deal!
その取引忘れたわけじゃないだろう
Say something!
なんとか　言えよ
It seems the Price I took from you before... has ran out juice.
以前　貴様から奪った代償は
電池に入れ　という事かな
In any case, it's too late.
ともかく　もう手遅れだ
I shall go back.
わらわは帰る
As such, this girl's life will end.
ゆえに　この娘の命が尽きる
This is good bye.
グッド バイだ
Go back where?
帰るって　何処にだよ
The Destination of Fate.
それは　運命の至る場所
Once more...
もう一度
Can you do it once more?
もう一度やってくれないか
I will pay for Himari's life with my own.
ひまりの命は俺の命で購う
That should work.
それでいいはずだろう
It's no use.
無駄だ
It's akin to love.
あれは恋みたいな物
Akin to the first kiss.
初めてのキスのようなもの
It only works once.
一度きりしか効かぬ
You'll never know until you try.
やって見なきゃ　分かんねぇだろう
Come on, hurry and take it.
ほら　早くやれよ
The Scorpion's Soul burning bright red.
赤く燃えるサソリの魂か
Very well.
よかろう
Let's initiate the Surivival Strategy.
生存戦略　しましょうか
Just as the black bunnies claimed,
黒い兎は言った通り　リンゴの木は生き返りました
the apple tree was revived.
Mary was overjoyed,
メリーさんは大喜び
dancing under the tree, blind to the three little lambs.
木の下で　ダンスばかりして
三匹の小羊達も目に入りません
However, the Goddess was furious.
しかし　女神様は激怒しました
It was, after all, a taboo.
やはりそれは　掟破りだったのです
The Goddess decided to punish Mary.
女神様は　メリーさんに罰を与える事にしました
But... the punishment was ultimately up to the Goddess's whim.
でも　その罰は　あくまで女神様の気まぐれで
Eeney, meeny, miny, moe!
どれにしようかな
The Goddess chose the smallest, youngest lamb.
女神様は三匹の中で一番小さな　幼い羊を選びました
The lamb she chose was a gentle and kind girl.
選ばれた小羊は　気立ての優しい素敵な女の子
Who likes to cook and knit,
料理と編み物が好きで
いつも二人の頼りない兄の心配ばかりしている
and always worries about her good-for-nothing brothers.
She was but a little girl.
小さいな女の子でした
Himari...
ひまり
The brother lambs who were left behind cried...
残された兄弟羊は言いました
O Goddess, why did you choose Himari?
女神様　どうしてひまりを選んだですか
だって　罰は
Because punishment...
Because punishment has to be the most unjust.
だって　罰は一番理不尽じゃないとね
Himari?
ひまりちゃん
Why?
どうして
Why can't it be me?!
どうして　俺じゃだめなんだ
Indeed, it can't.
そう　君じゃだめさ
Don't you agree?
だよね
The Wheel That Spins Us 'Round
subete ga moshi kimerarete tara
If everything was written in stone
全てが欲しい
繋がれたいたら
bokura wa doushite mogaku no darou
Why have we been resisting our fate?
僕らはどうして
もがくのだろう
sore wa kimi ja nai
It's not you
それは君じゃない
kimi no sei ja nai
It's not your fault
君のせいじゃない
kanashimi wa mou takusan nanda
I've had enough misery
苦しみはもう沢山なんだ
dakara sou ja nai
You're mistaken
だからそうじゃない
夢のままじゃない
ima no mama ja nai
Fate can be changed
umaku tsutaekirenai kedo
I can't explain it, but
上手く伝えきれないけど
Dear my future
Dear your future
Dear you future
Is this the punishment bestowed to us?
これが俺達の罰なのか
認めないぞ
I won't accept it.
俺はこの体の全てを焼き尽くしても
Even if my body was to burn to ashes,
I won't give up on you.
お前は諦めない
Survival Strategy. I won't give up.
生存戦略　諦めないよ